on this video I would like to share with
you advice for programmers given by some
of the best programmers of all time I've
been listening to The Lex Friedman
podcast with Legends like the creator of
Java or the creator of C plus plus among
many others and today I bring you a
compilation of the notes I have taken
that I hope can be helpful for you if
you like this kind of content and you
would like to see more of it then please
consider leaving a like and subscribing
to the channel just two clicks like And
subscribe it's free for you but it helps
me a lot now let's get started John
Carmack is one of the best computer
programmers ever Pioneer of 3D Graphics
he was the lead programmer of legendary
games like Wolfstein 3D doom and Quake
now he is working as the CTO of oculus
VR at meta and this is how he answered
the question what makes a good
programmer being proud about like a
specific architecture or specific
technology or specific code sequence
that you've done it's great to get a
little smile like a tiny little dopamine
hit for that but the the top level
metric should be that you're building
things of value cases that providing
actual value for people building useful
things for our users is what our Focus
as developers should be on rather than
focusing too much on the tech
architecture or algorithms that we use
he also talks about how by making useful
products we are making the world a
better place I mean it sounds triter
corny but I fundamentally do think
that's how you make the world a better
place if you have given more value to
people than it took you and your team to
create people have they've gone from
something of lesser value chosen to use
your product and their life feels better
for that and if you've produced that
economically that's that's a really good
thing and this is what he thinks about
the value of obsessing over something
and working hard rather than having work
life balance I you know work life
balance once versus kind of your life's
work where there's a small subset of the
people that can be very happy being
obsessive about things and you know
Obsession can often get things done that
just practical prudent pedestrian work
won't or at least won't for a very long
time of course this depends on the kind
of work we are doing if we are doing our
lives work our Masterpiece our Magnus
Opus obsessing over it might be the way
to go James Gosling the creator of a
tiny unknown language called Java also
talks about the value of working hard
the people who say you should work smart
not hard
they pretty much always fail that's just
just a recipe for disaster he also
advises young people to not be afraid of
risks and do stupid things don't be
afraid of risk it's okay to do stupid
things once and he brings up a topic
that we developers don't talk much about
ethics I started to think about ethical
choices in my life a big science fiction
fan I got to thinking about just about
every technical decision I make
in terms of are you building Blade
Runner or Star Trek which which Future
Would you rather live in I guess what he
means is that we developers have the
power of creation at our fingertips and
we should spend time thinking what kind
of word are we building we should all
reflect on what kind of jobs we would
say no to like working for an oppressive
government or for a company building
harmful products Bjorn straws troop the
creator of C plus plus says that it is
good for a professional programmer to
know at least five programming languages
I mean if you're a monoclot you are
likely to think that your own culture is
the only ones period so everybody else's
a good learning of a foreign language
and a foreign country is important it
helps you think and be a better person
with programming languages you become a
better programmer now once you've got to
the wager five is not that long it's the
second one that's most important he
recommends that we learn machine code
and C plus plus then learn a functional
programming language like Haskell and
choose other language to be able to
build something quickly like python
JavaScript or Ruby George Hots a
legendary programmer and hacker famous
on the iPhone jailbreaking scene ensued
by Sony for hacking into a PlayStation
says that the best way to learn to code
is to have a problem we want to solve
we're never going to learn programming
by watching a video called learn
programming the only way to learn
programming I think everyone I've ever
met who can program well learned it all
the same way they had something they
wanted to do and then they tried to do
it and then they were like oh well okay
this is kind of you know be nice if the
computer could kind of do this thing and
then you know that's how you learn you
just keep pushing on a project
I super agree with this nothing is
better than learning by doing and
learning to solve a problem not just
learning to learn by using learning as a
vehicle to accomplish something else
Travis oliphan the creator of numpy
scipy and Anaconda has a pretty good
list of what makes a good programmer I
would say there's a number of things
couple things one is curiosity like you
I think a programmer without curiosity
is uh mundane like you'll lose interest
you'll do your best work if we are not
curious we're going to have a hard time
staying up to date as developers and
growing in our career learning new
things should not feel like a chore it
should feel like a hobby using other
people's work right don't be afraid that
somehow you're like you should do it all
like nobody does really you want to cut
and paste but but not blindly oh this is
what this means oh this is what it's
doing and understand as much as you can
so it's critical that's where the
Curiosity comes in if you're just
blindly cutting and pasting you're not
gonna understand it's okay to copy paste
someone else's work but the least thing
we can do as developers is to understand
what the code is doing and why it is
working when talking about the kind of
people that he hires he talks about
humility and wanting to learn one of the
big things I look for is somebody that
fundamentally recognizes their need to
learn to learn like one of the values
that we we have and all of the things we
do is learning if somebody thinks they
know it all they're going to struggle
thank you for watching this video and
please let me know in the comments what
advice do you like the most if you have
some advice to share please leave it on
the comments because I'm going to be
looking at them right now and don't
forget if you want to Learn Python
JavaScript react react native go among
many other things for absolutely free
click the link below and I will see you
there honor though see you on the next
video bye